

ABOUT ME

Working in collaboration with product managers, developers, executives, design teams I help take products and make them into industry leading solutions. Leading user research and testing efforts, gathering market research, understanding business goals and knowing the capabilities and limitations of the technology are necessary for success. Then translating these into simple user personas, user journey maps, components, sitemaps, interaction patterns, wireframes and prototypes. Iterating and reevaluating features and roadmaps based on data and testing to make and refine world class experiences.

By helping organizations implement prescriptive levels of UX process it allows us to range from the simplest of iterative processes to more complex processes for the largest of features. This is especially helpful in smaller organizations and organizations that haven't had a strong UX presence. It can allow us to work and move faster on the smaller features while a fuller process can be injected within the larger product and development processes for future releases. This then adds speed to the entire cycle. Testing design prototypes rather than developed software significantly cuts our time spent redeveloping features that missed the mark.

Bringing the cross organizational teams together to collaborate on the products helps build trust and speed helps to ensure we deliver features that meet customer needs, user requirements, and business goals. Uniting teams in these efforts helps to crate a feeling of ownership for the vision of the product. Cross collaboration also generates more ideas from a more diverse group and can lead to unexpected insights and innovations.

Retaining the UX/UI integrity of the products can be a difficult task. By implementing living component and pattern libraries accessible to everyone that can live and change with user needs and business goals. This method facilitates UX at scale by democratization of the styles and patterns into replicable defined experiences. Then we can more quickly and easily iterate because we are all speaking the same design language. This library is not simply a design artifact but should also be used by teams across the organization to ensure consistency as well as facilitate easy future changes.

COI

CONTACT



801.726.4617



steven@stevenjeppesen.com



linkedin.com/in/stevenjeppesen



EDUCATION



Utah State University

Bachelors of Fine Art Graphic Design

Associates German Language



Cooper

Interaction Design Workshop



EXPERIENCE

2018

Overstock.com | Senior UX Product Designer | April 2018 – Present | \$801.947.3100

- Lead the User Experience, UX Vision and strategy for Overstocks enterprise software that allows overstocks partners to get products onto the retail website.
- Ran a design inventory and implemented a component & pattern library to bring a new level of consistency.
- Ran a platform inventory to evaluate sitemap efficiency.
- Run user testing both in person and remotely.
- Work with product managers, engineer teams, leadership, and other key stake holders to meet both business and user needs.
- Design and create fully-interactive prototypes & click-throughs to better communicate user stories to executives, engineers, and users.

2015

NICE inContact | Sr. Interaction Designer | August 2015 – April 2018 | \$801.320.3200

- Lead the interaction and visual design for multiple SaaS based applications.
- Create new experiences that answer market problems and make our software a market leader.
- · Run user testing both in person and remotely.
- Work alongside product managers & engineer teams to meet both business and user needs.
- Assist in producing style guides and interaction specification sheets for engineers.
- Design and create fully-interactive prototypes & click-throughs to better communicate user stories to executives, engineers, and users.

2012

FranklinCovey | UX Designer | March 2012 - August 2015 | \$801.817.1776

- Design and direct the UX of multiple sites, apps, and marketing micro-sites in a team environment.
- Use user stories and other data to create compelling navigation and page layout in both native and responsive web environments.
- Created a new fully responsive template system for marketing emails. This helped the marketing department be faster to market and more agile.
- Code full websites, micro-sites and marketing emails using best practices and standards.